Most teams do not have an LLM problem. They have an LLM operations problem.
This is llm_gateway: one endpoint to manage all your LLM traffic with routing,
failover, policy control, caching, and observability.
Without a gateway, auth patterns drift, costs become unclear, and debugging is hard.
llm_gateway centralizes control so teams can govern model access consistently.
The Go backend exposes familiar chat and embedding endpoints.
A Next.js dashboard manages providers, routes, API keys, spend groups,
cache settings, and audit logs.
In Providers, you can register multiple LLM backends and monitor health.
The gateway tracks failures, applies retries, and supports failover for resilience.
Routes let you map a stable slug to provider and model configuration.
You can apply system prompts, token limits, and fallback providers
without changing application code.
For security, llm_gateway supports JWT and gateway API keys.
Keys can be scoped by provider and model, with rate limits and request controls.
Cost rules are defined per provider and model.
Spend is estimated from token usage and can be grouped by team or project
for practical chargeback.
Redis caching improves repeated non-stream chat performance and lowers token spend.
Audit logs capture end-to-end request traces for debugging and compliance.
Market LLM offerings are endpoints.
llm_gateway is a control plane across endpoints:
provider-neutral, operations-first, and governance-ready.
With llm_gateway, teams deliver GenAI faster with better reliability,
cost control, and platform-level visibility.